Guide to the D. Michael Quinn Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- March 1999 Acquisition, circa 1910-circa 1999; 5.5; (9 boxes)
  - Personal Papers (Restricted)
    - Brigham Young, 1993; 1 VHS video cassette (Box 89)
    - "Tapes of talks", 1990s; 3 audio cassettes (Box 89)
    - Financial records, 1988-1989; 15 (Box 90)
    - Financial records, 1988-1991; 15 (Box 91)
    - Photographs of D. Michael Quinn and members of his family, circa 1910-1990; 8 (Box 92)
    - "LDS Historical Dept., Quinn's employee years", 1972-1973 (Box 92)
    - "Visitor's guide to driving in Utah", 1994 (Box 92)
    - Writings and correspondence of D. Michael Quinn, 1990s; 9 (Box 93)
    - Writings and correspondence of D. Michael Quinn, 1990s; 10 (Box 94)
- June 2003 Acquisition, circa 1970-circa 2001; 10.75; (14 boxes)
  Boxes 98-108: Restricted during the lifetime of D. Michael Quinn.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 758
  Research files include notes, printed material, and copies of primary sources on Mormon history, focusing on sexuality and same-sex relationships. Personal papers consists of correspondence, writings, notes, and personal documents that document Quinn's life from the 1990s-2000s.
  - Research Files
    - Research files on Mormon history, undated (Box 95)
    - Research files on sexuality, undated (Box 95)
    - Research files on Mormon history, undated (Box 95)
    - "Notes of interviews concerning current Mormon polygamy", undated (Box 95)
    - "Personal survey of experience concerning family, religion and sexuality", 1994; 3 (Box 95)
    - Videocassettes
      Restricted fragile material.
      - Biography: Brigham Young: Architect of Faith, undated; WAMSSS2692_0008; 1; 00:59:56 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102417996)
      - In Search of History: Mormon Rebellion, episode #H113, 1997 November 14; WAMSSS2692_0009; 1; 00:54:27 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102418002)
      - Joe Hill, KUED 7, 1998; WAMSSS2692_0010; 1; 01:27:03 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102418069)
      - Legacies, a documentary by Sean Weakland, 30 minutes, 1996; WAMSSS2692_0011; 1; 00:32:15 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102418028)
      - Nightline, Channel 4, Mormons and homosexuality, undated; WAMSSS2692_0012; 1; 05:25:11 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102418036)
      - The Mormon State I: The Message; The Mormon State II: Power and Dissidence. Producer: Claude Grenier, Journalist: Cecile Rodrigue, Canadian Broadcast Corporation, 1998; WAMSSS2692_0013; 1; 00:49:29 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102418044)
      - Unsung Heroes and Pearl Harbor (Hawaii) Sunday December 7, 1941 (History), 2001 May 26; WAMSSS2692_0014; 01:02:39 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102418051)
        Captain Mervyn S. Bennion's heroic defense of his ship, USS West Virginia depicted.
    - A Matter of Principle: Polygamy in the Mountain West, 1991; 1
    - Promontory, KUED 7, University of Utah, 57 minutes, 2002; 1
    - Joe Hill, KUED 7, duplicate, 1998; 1
    - An Office and a Gamofite, original mix CD, 1
    - Research notes relating to Early Mormonism and the Magic World View, 1990s; 35 (Box 97)
  - Personal Papers (Restricted)
    - "Mormons and Gays", 1970s-1980s; 4 (Box 98)
    - "The Diasporan Mormons," by Robert Smith Jordan, 1990s; 5 (Box 98)
    - "Writings and correspondence from Russell Kinkade", 1990s; 4 (Box 98)
    - Writings of Others, 1990s-2000s; 10 (Box 98)
    - Unsorted research files, 1990s; 3 (Box 98)
    - Photographs, 1990s, undated; 4 (Box 98)
    - Audio recordings of D. Michael Quinn and broadcasts relating to Mormon history, 1990s; (12 audio cassettes) (Box 99)
      - Religion on the Line: Polygamy, Part I, 1998 August 30; 1; 01:58:53; The program is distorted at times. (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393521)
      - Religion on the Line: Polygamy, Part 2, 1998 August 30; 1; 01:58:57; A buzz can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393539)
      - "Four Kinds of Homophobia", 20th Anniversary Affirmation Conference: Gay & Lesbian Mormons, 1997 August 22; 1; 00:53:14 (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393547)
      - "All Alike Unto God", 1998 February 24; 1; 00:15:57; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393554)
      - "Answers to History Questions, Sunstone, 1997; 1; 01:30:01; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393562)
        Salt Lake City, Utah
      - "Inside the Mormon Hierarchy", Sunstone, 1997; 1; 01:28:34 (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393570)
        San Jose, California
      - Author Meets Critics: Mormon Hierarchy: Extensions of Power, Sunstone, 1997; 1; 01:31:28 (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393588)
      - "Women and Priesthood", KRCL Radio Interview, 1998 January 20; 1; 00:32:29; A warble can be heard in the audio. (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393596)
      - "Inside the Mormon Hierarchy", Sunstone, undated; 1; 01:32:46 (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393604)
        Washington, D.C.
      - Pearl Harbor and Captain Mervyn S. Bennion KSL's Movie Show / Doug Wright comments on Robert E. Vernon letter, 2001 May 25 and June 1; 1; 01:30:10; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393612)
      - "Mormonism and the Magic World View", D. Michael Quinn autograph party, 1998 December 18; 1; 01:22:26; A high amount of hiss and static can be heard on the tape. High background noise can also be heard. (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393620)
        The introduction is by Kent Walgren.
      - "Mormonism and the Magic World View", D. Michael Quinn autograph party, 1998 December 18; 1; 01:49:07; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 99, Item barcode 39002091393638)
        The introduction is by K. Walgren.
    - Correspondence, incoming and outgoing, 1996-1998; 43 (Box 100)
    - Correspondence, incoming and outgoing, 1998-2001; 39 (Box 101)
    - Correspondence, incoming and outgoing, 2001; 7 (Box 102)
    - Newsletters, bulletins, fliers, 1990s-2000s; 19 (Box 102)
    - Papers relating to J. Reuben Clark, 1990s; 52 (Box 103)
    - "Victor Burner materials", 1990s (Box 103)
    - Writings of D. Michael Quinn, 1990s; 25 (Box 104)
    - Writings and reviews about D. Michael Quinn, 1990s-2000s; 9 (Box 104)
    - Newspaper clippings relating to Mormon history and to sexuality, 1990s; 8 (Box 104)
    - Desk calendars, 1996-1997; 2 (Box 105)
    - Diaries, 1988-2000; 7 (Box 105)
    - Legal papers, 1980s-1990s; 5 (Box 105)
    - Family papers, 1980s-1990s; 3 (Box 105)
    - Printed material relating to "Gay community", 2000s; 4 (Box 105)
    - "Entertainment", 1999-2001; 3 (Box 105)
    - Notes for learning Spanish, 1990s (Box 105)
    - Mexican travel documents, 1999; 2 (Box 105)
    - Personal documents and ephemera, 1960s (Box 105)
    - Memorabilia, photographs, and audiocassette, 1950s-1960s (Box 105)
      - Mike Temple when a tour guide, 1967; 1; 00:46:35; The program is distorted at times. (Box 105, Item barcode 39002091393703)
    - Affirmation writing awards contest, 2000; 4 (Box 106)
    - Audio recordings, 1980s; 4 audio cassettes (Box 107)
      - "Affirmation", 1985 April 21; 1; 01:03:13; The program is distorted at times. There is some phasing in the sound for the first 31 minutes of the program. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091393653)
        Songs from a female singer can be heard from 01:03:14 until the end of the tape.
      - Sam Campbell and CLP, 1985 April 8; 1; 01:02:29; The program is distorted at times. Static can be heard. There is a warble in the audio. Phasing can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091393661)
      - Sam Campbell and CLP, 1985 April 8; 1; 00:11:58; The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091393679)
      - [?]na Mae Mu[?], "Affirmation", 1985 April 21; 1; 00:48:01; The program is distorted at times. Audio drop outs can be heard at times. High background noise can be heard. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091393687)
    - Wall calendars, 2000-2001; 2 (Box 108 Oversize)
    - Cartoons, undated; 2 (Box 108 Oversize)
- February 2007 Acquisition, circa 1960-circa 1989; 1.46; (5 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 936
  Not arranged in any particular order
  The acquisition includes photographs documenting Quinn's travels, likely in the 1970s, personal correspondence, and one audio recording.
  - Correspondence, 1960s, undated; 7 (Box 109)
  - Photographs (slides), 1960s-1980s (Box 110)
  - Photographs (slides), 1960s-1980s (Box 111)
  - Photographs (slides), 1960s-1980s (Box 112)
  - Photographs (slides), 1960s-1980s (Box 113)
  - Photographs (slides), 1970s (Box 114)
  - Children, Mike, Jan, undated; 1; 00:15:51; The program is distorted at times. (Box 114, Item barcode 39002091393695)
- October 2008 Acquisition, 1976-2008; 17.76; (39 boxes)
  Arranged roughly chronologically.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1046
  The acquisition consists of lecture notes, drafts of writings, correspondence, audio recordings of Quinn, and other personal papers that document the life of D. Michael Quinn from the 1970s to the 2000s.
  - Brigham Young University lecture notes, 1976-1988; 22 (Box 115)
  - Brigham Young University lecture notes, 1977-1988; 17 (Box 116)
  - Salt Lake Community College lecture notes, 2001 (Box 116)
  - University of Southern California lecture notes, 2000-2002; 2 (Box 116)
  - University of Southern California lecture notes, 2001 (Box 117)
  - Affirmation writing awards contest, 2002-2005; 4 (Box 117)
  - Correspondence, 1981-2001 (Box 117)
  - "Personal memorandums", 2002 (Box 117)
  - "Entertainment", 2002 (Box 117)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, A-F, 2002 (Box 117)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, G-Y, 2002; 2 (Box 118)
  - Correspondence, incoming, A-N, 2002; 4 (Box 118)
  - Correspondence, incoming, O-Y, 2002; 6 (Box 119)
  - "Personal memorandums", 2003 (Box 120)
  - "Entertainment", 2003 (Box 120)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, 2003; 7 (Box 120)
  - Correspondence, incoming, A-N, 2003; 6 (Box 121)
  - Correspondence, incoming, O-Y, 2003; 6 (Box 122)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Y, 2003 (Box 123)
  - "Personal memorandums", 2004 (Box 123)
  - "Entertainment", 2004 (Box 123)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, A-L, 2004; 6 (Box 123)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, M-Y, 2004; 5 (Box 124)
  - Correspondence, incoming, A-Ba, 2004; 2 (Box 124)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Be-Mac, 2004; 8 (Box 125)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Maj-Wh, 2004; 7 (Box 126)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Wi-Y, 2004 (Box 127)
  - "Personal memorandums", 2005 (Box 127)
  - "Entertainment", 2005 (Box 127)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, A-L, 2005; 7 (Box 127)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, N-Y, 2005; 5 (Box 128)
  - Correspondence, incoming, A-Ba, 2005; 3 (Box 128)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Be-Hi, 2005; 8 (Box 129)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Ho-N, 2005; 6 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence, incoming, O-T, 2005; 7 (Box 131)
  - Correspondence, incoming, U-Y, 2005; 5 (Box 132)
  - "Personal memorandums", 2006 (Box 132)
  - "Entertainment", 2006 (Box 132)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, A, 2006 (Box 132)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, B-P, 2006; 9 (Box 133)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, Q-Y, 2006; 3 (Box 134)
  - Correspondence, incoming, A-B, 2006; 5 (Box 134)
  - Correspondence, incoming, C-F, 2006; 7 (Box 135)
  - Correspondence, incoming, G-K, 2006; 7 (Box 136)
  - Correspondence, incoming, L-P, 2006; 8 (Box 137)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Q-V, 2006; 7 (Box 138)
  - Correspondence, incoming, W-Z, 2006; 2 (Box 139)
  - "Personal memorandums", 2007 (Box 139)
  - "Entertainment", 2007 (Box 139)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, A-H, 2007; 4 (Box 139)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, J-Y, 2007; 6 (Box 140)
  - Correspondence, incoming, A, 2007; 3 (Box 140)
  - Correspondence, incoming, A (continued)-D, 2007; 8 (Box 141)
  - Correspondence, incoming, D (continued)-H, 2007; 6 (Box 142)
  - Correspondence, incoming, H (continued)-Mc, 2007; 8 (Box 143)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Ma-Pet, 2007; 9 (Box 144)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Po-Tw, 2007; 8 (Box 145)
  - Correspondence, incoming, U-Z, 2007; 3 (Box 146)
  - Writings and photographs of paintings by Joyce Workman Quinn, 1961-2007; 5 (Box 146)
  - Writings by Joyce Workman Quinn, undated; 3 (Box 147)
  - Talks and articles by D. Michael Quinn, 2000s; 14 (Box 147)
  - Talks and articles by D. Michael Quinn, 2000s; 24 (Box 148)
  - Talks and articles by D. Michael Quinn, 2000s; 7 (Box 149)
  - Reviews of Quinn's books, 2000s; 2 (Box 149)
  - Media references to Quinn, 2000s (Box 149)
  - Media references to Quinn, 2000s (Box 150)
  - Newsletters, 2000s; 5 (Box 150)
  - Newsletters, 2000s; 4 (Box 151)
  - Articles on Mormonism, 2000s (Box 151)
  - Notes for "Joseph Smith's Experience of a Methodist 'Camp Meeting' in 1820", 2005-2006 (Box 151)
  - Fragment of a stone gorget from New York State, undated (Box 152)
  - Sunstone Symposium, audio recording (CDs), 2006; 5 audio CDs (Box 152)
  - "A Sunstone town meeting," (audiocassette), 2005; 1; 01:01:04; The program is distorted at times. (Box 152, Item barcode 39002091393646)
  - Promontory, KUED 7, University of Utah, 57 minutes, 2002; WAMSSS2692_0003; 1; 00:12:49 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102370161)
  - The Mormons, DVD recording, 2007 (Box 152)
  - Scouts Honor, 56:46, undated; WAMSSS2692_0004; 1; 00:57:32 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102370179)
  - Faith and Doubt at Ground Zero [by Helen Whitney], undated; WAMSSS2692_0005; 1; 00:57:41 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102370187)
  - Photograph album containing reproductions of family photographs, undated (Box 153 Oversize)
- January 2014 Acquisition, 2000-2001; 2.75; (3 boxes)
  - Sunstone Symposium, typescript and program, 2000-04; 2 folders (Box 154)
  - Affirmation Writing Awards contest, binder, 2001 (Box 155)
  - Affirmation Writing Awards contest, binder, 2001 (Box 156)
- January 2015 Acquisition, 1992; 0.25; (1 box)
  - LDS Church interviews, typescripts with corrections, 1992 (Box 157)
- November 2018 Acquisition, 1986-2013; 43.75; (41 boxes)
  - Financial records, 1986-1999; 9 folders (Box 158)
  - Financial records, 2000-2009; 10 folders (Box 159)
  - Financial records, 2010-2011; 2 folders (Box 160)
  - Writings by others, circa 2000s-2010s; 13 folders (Box 161)
    - Audiovisual material, circa 2000s; 1 (Box 162)
    - Electronic material, circa 2000s; 14 (Box 163)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-C, 2008; 34 folders (Box 165)
    - Calendar, 2008 (Box 166)
  - Incoming correspondence, C-H, 2008; 26 folders (Box 167)
  - Incoming correspondence, H-O, 2008; 23 folders (Box 168)
  - Incoming correspondence, P-Y, 2008; 28 folders (Box 169)
  - Writings, research material and correspondence, 2009; 28 folders (Box 170)
    - Calendar and diary memos, 2009 (Box 171)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-D, 2009; 22 folders (Box 172)
  - Incoming correspondence, D-K, 2009; 17 folders (Box 173)
  - Incoming correspondence, K-N, 2009; 14 folders (Box 174)
  - Incoming correspondence, N-U, 2009; 22 folders (Box 175)
  - Correspondence, writing,and research material, 2009-2010; 28 folders (Box 176)
    - Calendar and diary types, 2010 (Box 177)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-C, 2010; 19 folders (Box 178)
  - Incoming correspondence, C-H, 2010; 17 folders (Box 179)
  - Incoming correspondence, H-K, 2010; 14 folders (Box 180)
  - Incoming correspondence, K-O, 2010; 18 folders (Box 181)
  - Incoming correspondence, O-T, 2010; 20 folders (Box 182)
  - Correspondence, published newsletters, and writings, 2010-2011; 21 folders (Box 183)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-C, 2011; 24 folders (Box 184)
  - Incoming correspondence, C, 2011; 14 folders (Box 185)
  - Incoming correspondence, C-K, 2011; 29 folders (Box 186)
  - Incoming correspondence, K-M, 2011; 20 folders (Box 187)
  - Incoming correspondence, M-P, 2011; 22 folders (Box 188)
  - Incoming correspondence, Q-T, 2011; 20 folders (Box 189)
  - Incoming correspondence, T-W, 2011; 22 folders (Box 190)
  - Writings and correspondence, 2012; 28 folders (Box 191)
    - Calendar, 2012 (Box 192)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-C, 2012; 22 folders (Box 193)
  - Incoming correspondence, C-D, 2012; 28 folders (Box 194)
  - Incoming correspondence, D-K, 2012; 27 folders (Box 195)
  - Incoming correspondence, K-N, 2012; 27 folders (Box 196)
  - Incoming correspondence, O-T, 2012; 27 folders (Box 197)
  - Incoming correspondence, T-W, 2012; 27 folders (Box 198)